FRANCHESKA GUZMÁN FLORES

Software Tester



Carolina, PR



787-410-9414



francheska.dev



francheska-guzman@outlook.com

About

Francheska has 8+ years of combined experience in manual and automated software testing, quality assurance, and web development. ISTQB/ASTQB Certified Tester with strong analytical skills, problem solver, detail-oriented, and interpersonal abilities.

Skills

Technical Skills: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ¡Query, Cypress, Mocha, Cucumber, Gherkin Language, WordPress, React.js, Node.js, Git, GitHub, Azure DevOps, Xcode Accessibility Inspector, Axe, SortSite (PowerMapper), Wave, Visual Studio Code, Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, Heroku.

Languages: Spanish (native), English (intermediate).

Work Experience

Abarca Health LLC - Pharmacy Benefit Manager (PBM) Company Software Test Engineer II

San Juan, PR

Apr 2022 - Present

- · Participate in the Scrum ceremonies and work closely with a team of Quality Engineers, Business Analysts, Software Engineers, and Product Owners.
- Create test plans, test suites, and test cases in Azure Test Plans.
- Run manual tests and perform manual regression testing in the Darwin web application.
- Use Datadog to monitor the web application.
- Query execution over the Microsoft SQL Server database.

INVID LLC - Information Technology Company Software QA Tester II

San Juan, PR Apr 2021 - Apr 2022

Contributed to the creation of guidelines to improve internal QA/QC procedures.

- Provided training about manual testing activities.
- Created and locally ran automated UI test scripts using Cypress, Cucumber, and Mocha.
- All duties and responsibilities mentioned in the previous role (QA Tester I).

Software QA Tester I Oct 2019 - Apr 2021

- Participated in the process of the Software Development Life Cycle (Scrum).
- Performed static testing in requirements and design (mockups).
- Created test plans, test suites, and test cases in Azure Test Plans.
- Ran manual tests and performed exploratory testing in web and mobile applications.
- Conducted usability/accessibility testing for WCAG 2.1, ADA, and Section 508 compliance by using tools such as the Xcode Accessibility Inspector, Axe, SortSite, and Wave.
- Reported and tracked issues identified during testing activities to ensure defect resolution and testing completion.
- Collaborated in the development of new ideas to resolve system issues and improve current systems.
- Basic query execution over the Microsoft SQL Server database.

New York Film Academy - School of Film and Acting

New York, NY

Front End Web Developer

Jul 2018 - Aug 2019

- Coded e-mail marketing campaigns and landing pages based on mockups and provided content.
- Segmented mailing lists by making queries on the database.
- · Delivered approved e-mail campaigns to the target market using both Campaigner and iContact email marketing automation platforms.

- Made updates to the New York Film Academy websites and WordPress sites.
- Coded the new version of the online applications.
- Debugged e-mail campaigns, landing pages, online applications, and websites.

Second Language Design - Creative and Marketing Agency Web Developer

New York, NY

Feb 2018 - Jul 2018

Sep 2014 - Jul 2018

- Developed WordPress sites for clients based on mockups and provided content.
- Performed QA testing across modern platforms and devices.
- Added meta tags for SEO and set up Google Analytics.
- Used Google Spreadsheets API for data collection.

uTest - Crowdsourced Software Testing Community

Remote

Software Tester

- Executed test cases in web and native applications.
- Performed exploratory testing to identify any GUI, functional, or technical bug.
- Performed localization testing by verifying translations from English to Latin American Spanish.
- Submitted detailed bug reports.

Projects

Weather Forecast

https://francheska-guzman.github.io/weather-forecast

Weather Forecast is a web app that provides information such as temperature, pressure, and humidity of five cities. Developed with React.js and requesting the data from a third party API.

Education

CodeBridge - Web Development Immersive Program

New York, NY

Certificate of Completion

2017

Per Scholas and General Assembly

Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA)

San Juan, PR

Accounting and Office Systems Administration

University of Puerto Rico, Río Piedras Campus

2015

Certifications

Certified Tester, Foundation Level Agile Tester (CTFL-AT)

American Software Testing Qualifications Board, Inc. (ASTQB)

International Software Testing Qualifications Board (ISTQB)

Credential ID: 22-CTFL-AT-00111-USA

Issued Apr 2022 - No Expiration Date

Certified Tester, AT*SQA Testing Essentials

Association for Testing and Software Quality Assurance, Inc. (AT*SQA)

Credential ID: 21-AT*Essentials-00008-USA

Issued Dec 2021 - No Expiration Date

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

Credential ID: 1041-2121

Issued Nov 2021 - No Expiration Date

Certified Tester, Foundation Level (CTFL)

American Software Testing Qualifications Board, Inc. (ASTQB)

International Software Testing Qualifications Board (ISTQB)

Credential ID: 21-CTFL-01698-USA

Issued Sep 2021 - No Expiration Date